Finding Aid for Solar Car Team (University of Michigan) publications, 1987-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Solar Car Team (University of Michigan) publications 1987-2001
University of Michigan. Solar Car Team.
1 linear feet
0323 Bimu 2
The Solar Car Team is an interdisciplinary student organization at the University of Michigan whose objectives are to design, finance, build and race a solar-powered vehicle from scratch. Publications Includes articles, brochures, directories, newsletters such as the Solar Car Express and the Southern Sun, press releases, programs, prospectuses and regulations regarding the various University of Michigan Solar Car Projects as well as the GM Sunrayce and the Sponsor World Solar Challenge. Also includes two histories describing the 1990 races.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred from the Solar Car Team (Donor No. 8010 ) in a series of accessions beginning in 1992.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open for research.
See historical sketch for Solar Car Team (University of Michigan) records.
Solar Car Publications (1 linear foot) are divided into six series. The first focuses on the 1990 Sunrayce and World Solar Challenge– Sunrunner. It contains official race regulations, newsletters, programs, brochures, magazines, and photocopies of articles on GM Sunrayce USA and the World Solar Challenge. This series also includes prospectuses which give early details on the budget for and design of the Sunrunner and press releases from News and Information Services, General Motors Corporation and the Henry Ford Museum and Greenfield Village.
It also includes two published histories. In Sunracing, Richard and Melissa King write about both the American and Australian races. Because of Michigan's great success in both races the Sunrunner features prominently in this history. It includes a narrative of the races and color photographs of many, but not all the entrants. The second history, Racing With the Sun: The 1990 World Solar Challenge by Chester R. Kyle focuses on the technical aspects of the cars and the race. There are black and white photographs of all the cars entered in the World Solar Challenge with their specifications. There are also rules and regulations for both the GM Sunrayce and World Solar Challenge
The second series focuses on the 1993 Sunrayce and World Solar Challenge– Maize & Blue. It includes brochures, a directory of team members, a fact sheet on the GM Sunrayce, the newsletter Solar Express covering the years 1991-1993, and press releases for both the GM Sunrayce and the World Solar Challenge.
The third series contains material on the 1995 Sunrayce– Solar Vision including the newsletter Solar Express for the years 1993-1995 and press releases on the GM Sunrayce.
The fourth series includes documentation on the 1997 Sunrayce– Wolverine, such as the newsletter Solar Express for 1997 as well as programs and regulations from the race.
The fifth series covers 1999 Sunrayce– MaizeBlaze. It includes brochures and newsclippings from the race and 1998-1999 issues of Solar Express.
The sixth series focuses on the 2001 World Solar Challenge– M-Pulse with brochures and programs from the race as well as issues of the newsletter Southern Sun.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Solar Car Team.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; Solar car express.; Southern sun.
Genre Terms:
Directories.; Newsletters.; Press releases.; Programs.; Regulations.; Student publications.; Histories.; Prospectuses.
- Publications
  - 1990 Sunrayce and World Solar Challenge--Sunrunner
    - Articles regarding Sunrunner and Sunrayce (Box 1)
    - Brochures 1990 regarding IBM Computer in U. of M. Sunrunner (Box 1)
    - Histories
      - Racing With the Sun: The 1990 World Solar Challenge by Chester R. Kyle, 1991 (Box 1)
      - Sunracing by Richard and Melissa King, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Newsclippings 1989-1991, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Shining News, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Solar Express, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Sunrayce Newsletter, 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Posters 1990 designed by Department of Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics (Box 1)
    - Press Releases 1987-1991, 7 folders (Box 1)
      (includes photographs and slides)
    - Programs 1987-1990 (Box 1)
    - Prospectuses
      - Solar-Powered Vehicle Design, 1989 (Box 1)
      - The University of Michigan Solar Car Team--Sunrunner, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Regulations
      - GM Sunrayce
        - Official Race Route Source Book, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Rayce Regulations: Florida to Michigan, 1990 (Box 1)
      - World Solar Challenge
        - Pre-Regulations--The 1990 World Solar Challenge, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Regulations: World Solar Challenge, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Regulations: 1991 Energy Challenge, 1990 (Box 1)
  - 1993 Sunrayce and World Solar Challenge--Maize & Blue
    - Brochures Undated (Box 1)
    - Directories
      - University of Michigan Solar Car Team, Undated (Box 1)
    - Fact Sheets
      - Sunrayce 93: Just the Facts, Undated (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Solar Express, 1991-1993 vol. 2, no. 1-6 (Box 1)
    - Press Releases 1993 (Box 1)
      (includes photograph)
  - 1995 Sunrayce--Solar Vision
    - Newsletters
      - Solar Express, vol. 3, no. 1-11, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
    - Press Releases June 1995 (Box 1)
  - 1997 Sunrayce--Wolverine
    - Newsletters
      - Solar Express, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Programs 1997 (Box 1)
    - Regulations 1997 (Box 1)
  - 1999 Sunrayce--MaizeBlaze
    - Brochures 1999 (Box 1)
    - Newsclippings 1999 (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Solar Express, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - 2001 World Solar Challege--M-Pulse
    - Brochures and programs undated (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Southern Sun, 2001 (Box 1)